<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Raspberry Pi on Mitchtech</title>
    <link>https://mitchtech.github.io/hugo-mitchtech/tags/raspberry-pi/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Raspberry Pi on Mitchtech</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Powered by [Hugo](//gohugo.io). Theme by [PPOffice](http://github.com/ppoffice).</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2013 07:07:30 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mitchtech.github.io/hugo-mitchtech/tags/raspberry-pi/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Raspberry Pi OpenCV Pan &amp; Tilt Face Tracker</title>
      <link>https://mitchtech.github.io/hugo-mitchtech/raspberry-pi-servo-face-tracker/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2013 07:07:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mitchtech.github.io/hugo-mitchtech/raspberry-pi-servo-face-tracker/</guid>
      <description>Create your own face tracking, pan and tilt camera on the Raspberry Pi!
This tutorial will demonstrate use of the OpenCV (computer vision) library to identify and track faces on the raspberry pi using two servos and a USB webcam. For the interested, I previously covered a more thorough overview of the installation of OpenCV from source here, however, I have found that the apt package is sufficient for all but the most bleeding edge of projects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Raspberry Pi Google Talk Robot</title>
      <link>https://mitchtech.github.io/hugo-mitchtech/raspberry-pi-google-talk-robot/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2013 02:06:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mitchtech.github.io/hugo-mitchtech/raspberry-pi-google-talk-robot/</guid>
      <description>Google Talk/Chat/Messenger is normally used by humans to interact with other humans. However, its underlying technology can also be used as a mechanism to implement software robots. Internet bots, also known as web robots, WWW robots or simply &amp;lsquo;bots&amp;rsquo; can also utilize the technology to perform automated functions over the web. There are many such bots in existence, offering a diverse spectrum of services from jokes (jokes@askme.im) to URL Shortening using bit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Raspberry Pi &#43; PWM RGB LED Strip</title>
      <link>https://mitchtech.github.io/hugo-mitchtech/raspberry-pi-pwm-rgb-led-strip/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2013 23:29:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mitchtech.github.io/hugo-mitchtech/raspberry-pi-pwm-rgb-led-strip/</guid>
      <description>This tutorial demonstrates how to easily use a Raspberry Pi to drive 12V RGB LED strips using Pulse Width Modulation (PWM). Out of the box, the Raspberry Pi has only one GPIO pin that is capable of pulse width modulation (PWM). However, thanks to the efforts of Richard Hirst and his servoblaster kernel module, standard GPIO pins can be used to perform PWM.
Note: The flashing of the LED strip due to PWM is only noticeable in the uploaded video; in reality, the colors progress smoothly without any visible flashing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Easily connect Raspberry Pi to Gmail, Facebook, Twitter &amp; more!</title>
      <link>https://mitchtech.github.io/hugo-mitchtech/connect-raspberry-pi-to-gmail-facebook-twitter-more/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2012 00:20:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mitchtech.github.io/hugo-mitchtech/connect-raspberry-pi-to-gmail-facebook-twitter-more/</guid>
      <description>Easily connect your Raspberry Pi to web services and social networks! This tutorial demonstrates how to painlessly send and receive Gmail on the Raspberry Pi from Python, which in turn, allows you to easily connect it to web services and social networks like Facebook, Twitter, and more! This would normally be well beyond the abilities of most users due to the inherent complexities of programming through social media APis, client/server authentication, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Raspberry Pi &#43; MSP430 &#43; SPI</title>
      <link>https://mitchtech.github.io/hugo-mitchtech/raspberry-pi-msp430-spi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2012 15:16:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mitchtech.github.io/hugo-mitchtech/raspberry-pi-msp430-spi/</guid>
      <description>This tutorial will explain how to communicate from the Raspberry Pi to an MSP430 Launchpad board (M430G2553 chip) using SPI.
Requirements  1 Raspberry pi (running Raspbian)
 1 MSP430 TI Launchpad
 3 wires
  Your raspberry pi should be running the newest version of Raspbian. To ensure your system is up-to-date please download and run rpi-update.
Wiring 
MSP430 Flash the below code to your MSP430 chip.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Raspberry Pi &#43; Arduino &#43; SPI</title>
      <link>https://mitchtech.github.io/hugo-mitchtech/raspberry-pi-arduino-spi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Aug 2012 11:35:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mitchtech.github.io/hugo-mitchtech/raspberry-pi-arduino-spi/</guid>
      <description>This tutorial will show you how to communicate from your raspberry pi to your arduino using 3-wire SPI.
Requirements  1 Raspberry pi (running Raspbian)
 1 Arduino
 4 wires
  Your raspberry pi should be running the newest version of Raspbian. To ensure your system is up-to-date please download and run rpi-update.
Wiring 
Arduino Open your Arduino ide and flash the below code to your Arduino.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dropbox on Raspberry Pi via SSHFS</title>
      <link>https://mitchtech.github.io/hugo-mitchtech/dropbox-on-raspberry-pi-via-sshfs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2012 22:54:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mitchtech.github.io/hugo-mitchtech/dropbox-on-raspberry-pi-via-sshfs/</guid>
      <description>This tutorial will demonstrate how to mount Dropbox (or any filesystem) over the network on the Raspberry Pi using SSHFS (Secure SHell FileSystem). For this procedure to work for your Dropbox share, you will need another machine somewhere that is running Dropbox, and is accessible to the Raspberry Pi via SSH.
Note: The following is not actually specific to the Raspberry Pi, nor to Dropbox. The tutorial generalizes for other systems and architectures that are not officially supported by Dropbox, as well as for mounting of other non Dropbox shares over the network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Peer Guardian on Raspberry Pi</title>
      <link>https://mitchtech.github.io/hugo-mitchtech/peer-guardian-on-raspberry-pi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jul 2012 22:52:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mitchtech.github.io/hugo-mitchtech/peer-guardian-on-raspberry-pi/</guid>
      <description>This tutorial will show how to compile and install Peer Guardian on a Raspberry Pi. The process requires the at least the 2012-06-18-wheezy-beta.zip or newer Debian image (or manual kernel re-compilation). This will NOT work with debian6-19-04-2012.zip since the kernel does not have net filtering enabled. Also, you will need a decent sized SD card (4GB at least) &amp;hellip; the dependencies alone require 382 MB.
First, install the required package dependencies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Raspberry Pi Physical Gmail Notifier</title>
      <link>https://mitchtech.github.io/hugo-mitchtech/raspberry-pi-physical-gmail-notifier/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jun 2012 04:20:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mitchtech.github.io/hugo-mitchtech/raspberry-pi-physical-gmail-notifier/</guid>
      <description>This tutorial will demonstrate how to easily turn your Raspberry Pi into a physical Gmail notifier, in only 10 lines of python! If the configured Gmail account has unread messages, the LED will be illuminated, otherwise dim. The project was inspired by the Arduino/Mac version by J4mie adapted for use on the Raspberry Pi.
Here is a diagram of the wiring of the LED with a 330 ohm resistor in series (created with Fritzing):</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arduino on Raspberry Pi</title>
      <link>https://mitchtech.github.io/hugo-mitchtech/arduino-on-raspberry-pi/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jun 2012 00:00:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mitchtech.github.io/hugo-mitchtech/arduino-on-raspberry-pi/</guid>
      <description>Connecting an Arduino to a Raspberry Pi is simple. In a terminal, install the Arduino IDE:
sudo apt-get install arduino  This will take a while to download and install all of the dependencies. Once completed, you can start the IDE from the terminal:
arduino  Or, from the LXDE menu, Electronics-&amp;gt;Arduino IDE. Note: This is IDE version 0018, and does not seem to recognize boards newer then the Duemilanove.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Raspberry Pi NES Emulator</title>
      <link>https://mitchtech.github.io/hugo-mitchtech/raspberry-pi-nes-emulator/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2012 23:50:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mitchtech.github.io/hugo-mitchtech/raspberry-pi-nes-emulator/</guid>
      <description>This tutorial will demonstrate how to install Nintendo NES/Famicom emulator on the Raspberry Pi running Debian. Begin by installing the necessary dependencies. In a terminal, enter:
sudo apt-get install scons libsdl1.2-dev libsdl1.2debian-esd subversion libgtk2.0-dev  Checkout the most recent sources using subversion:
&amp;lt;del&amp;gt;svn checkout https://fceultra.svn.sourceforge.net/svnroot/fceultra/fceu fceultra&amp;lt;/del&amp;gt;  The repo has moved here:
svn checkout svn://svn.code.sf.net/p/fceultra/code/fceu fceultra  Change directory into the root of the source tree
cd fceultra/  Compile and install FCEU using the scons build tool:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Raspberry Pi &#43; OpenCV</title>
      <link>https://mitchtech.github.io/hugo-mitchtech/raspberry-pi-opencv/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2012 23:41:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mitchtech.github.io/hugo-mitchtech/raspberry-pi-opencv/</guid>
      <description>OpenCV is a suite of powerful computer vision tools. Here is a quick overview of how I installed OpenCV on my Raspberry Pi with debian6-19-04-2012. The guide is based on the official OpenCV Installation Guide on Debian and Ubuntu. Before you begin, make sure you have expanded your SD card to allow for the install of OpenCV. Its a big package with lots of dependencies. You can follow my instructions here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Raspberry Pi Root FS on USB Drive</title>
      <link>https://mitchtech.github.io/hugo-mitchtech/raspberry-pi-root-fs-on-usb-drive/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2012 00:49:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mitchtech.github.io/hugo-mitchtech/raspberry-pi-root-fs-on-usb-drive/</guid>
      <description>This tutorial will demonstrate how to install the Debian root filestem (ie. &amp;lsquo;/&amp;rsquo;) on a USB drive instead of the SD card. The SD card still retains the /boot partion and swap space. This requires a modified kernel to support the USB storage. You can download the minimal modified kernel and modules here or follow my guide on how to compile it for yourself.
In either case, begin by installing the Debian image as you normally would to an SD card.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Raspberry Pi Kernel Compile</title>
      <link>https://mitchtech.github.io/hugo-mitchtech/raspberry-pi-kernel-compile/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jun 2012 04:51:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mitchtech.github.io/hugo-mitchtech/raspberry-pi-kernel-compile/</guid>
      <description>This tutorial will demonstrate how to cross compile the kernel for the Raspberry Pi on Ubuntu 12.04 LTS. The kernel is functional with both the Debian and Arch Linux Raspberry Pi images.
UPDATE: Alternatively, you can use the following Ansible playbook playbook-raspi_kernel_crosscompile. Note that you have to edit host_vars/localhost.yml file with your local sudo password.
git clone https://github.com/chrismeyersfsu/playbook-raspi_kernel_crosscompile ansible-playbook -i localhost.yml site.yml -vvvv  First, install the package dependencies, git and the cross-compilation toolchain:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wordpress on Raspberry Pi</title>
      <link>https://mitchtech.github.io/hugo-mitchtech/wordpress-on-raspberry-pi/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jun 2012 04:29:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mitchtech.github.io/hugo-mitchtech/wordpress-on-raspberry-pi/</guid>
      <description>This tutorial will demonstrate how to install and host Wordpress on Raspberry Pi. This process assumes you have Debian for Raspberry Pi installed on an SD card. If not, see RPi Easy SD card setup.
Install Apache Wordpress runs on the Apache2 web server. To setup Apache, follow the instructions in my previous post, Raspberry Pi and Apache.
Install MySQL and PHP Begin by installing the required dependencies. From a terminal:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Raspberry Pi &#43; Apache</title>
      <link>https://mitchtech.github.io/hugo-mitchtech/raspberry-pi-apache/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jun 2012 04:03:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mitchtech.github.io/hugo-mitchtech/raspberry-pi-apache/</guid>
      <description>Its quite easy to install the Apache web server on the Raspberry Pi. This process assumes you have Debian for Raspberry Pi installed on an SD card. If not, see RPi Easy SD card setup. Open a terminal (or login via SSH) and install the package with apt-get:
sudo apt-get install apache2  UPDATE: 9/18/12: The following group creation error appears to have been corrected in an updated package and should no longer be necessary.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Easy GUI Install &amp; Re-Partition Raspberry Pi on Ubuntu</title>
      <link>https://mitchtech.github.io/hugo-mitchtech/easy-gui-install-re-partition-raspberry-pi-on-ubuntu/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jun 2012 00:15:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mitchtech.github.io/hugo-mitchtech/easy-gui-install-re-partition-raspberry-pi-on-ubuntu/</guid>
      <description>Easy Install &amp;amp; Resize the SD Card on the Raspberry Pi on Ubuntu.
First, open a terminal and install the ImageWriter and GParted utilities with apt-get
sudo apt-get install usb-imagewriter gparted  Assuming you are starting with a fresh install, download the newest release from the Raspberry Pi download site:
[http://www.raspberrypi.org/downloads](http://www.raspberrypi.org/downloads)  Extract the downloaded archive, and then open ImageWriter:
imagewriter  Select the desired .img file and target device, in this case, debian6-19-04-2012.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ralink/Realtek Wireless Dongle (rt3070) on the Raspberry Pi</title>
      <link>https://mitchtech.github.io/hugo-mitchtech/realtek-wireless-dongle-rt3070-on-the-raspberry-pi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jun 2012 18:49:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mitchtech.github.io/hugo-mitchtech/realtek-wireless-dongle-rt3070-on-the-raspberry-pi/</guid>
      <description>[caption id=&amp;ldquo;attachment_608&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;ldquo;alignnone&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;300&amp;rdquo; caption=&amp;ldquo;Realtek WiFi dongle&amp;rdquo;][/caption]
Scenario You have a HAWKING HWUN3 Hi-Gain Wireless Adapter dongle that you want to use on your Raspberry Pi running debian.
Note: the same set of steps will probably work for other variations of Ralink/Realtek wifi dongles [rt2561,rt2661,rt2860,rt2870,rt3070,rt3071,rt3090].
The Problem The standard release (debian6-19-04-2012.zip) contains the needed drivers however, the firmware needed is not included. The following tutorial will describe how to get and &amp;ldquo;install&amp;rdquo; the needed firmware.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Raspberry Pi Audio</title>
      <link>https://mitchtech.github.io/hugo-mitchtech/raspberry-pi-audio/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jun 2012 18:42:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mitchtech.github.io/hugo-mitchtech/raspberry-pi-audio/</guid>
      <description>Currently, the audio drivers for the Raspberry Pi are still in beta, and as such come disabled in the standard release (debian6-19-04-2012.zip). Here&amp;rsquo;s a quick way to get it up and running for both the HDMI as well as the analog output. Open up a terminal and install the alsa (Advanced Linux Sound Architecture) utility package:
sudo apt-get install alsa-utils  Now load the sound driver using modprobe:
sudo modprobe snd_bcm2835  By default output will be automatic (HDMI if supported, else analog).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Install Quake 3 on Raspberry Pi</title>
      <link>https://mitchtech.github.io/hugo-mitchtech/install-quake-3-on-raspberry-pi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jun 2012 18:17:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mitchtech.github.io/hugo-mitchtech/install-quake-3-on-raspberry-pi/</guid>
      <description>Here is the easiest possible way to install Quake 3 on the Raspberry Pi with debian6-19-04-2012. Just copy and paste the following in a terminal on the Pi:
cd ~ wget http://radium.hexxeh.net/quake3.zip wget http://www.andershizzle.com/Q3%20Demo%20Paks.zip unzip quake3.zip unzip Q3\ Demo\ Paks.zip rm quake3.zip rm Q3\ Demo\ Paks.zip mv ./baseq3/pak* ./quake3/baseq3/ rm -rf ./baseq3/ chmod +x /home/pi/quake3/start.sh chmod +x /home/pi/quake3/ioquake3.arm chmod +x /home/pi/quake3/ioq3ded.arm  Note: After reports of connection issues with the downloads, I have hosted mirror versions of the two files here:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VNC setup on Raspberry Pi from Android</title>
      <link>https://mitchtech.github.io/hugo-mitchtech/vnc-setup-on-raspberry-pi-from-android/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jun 2012 18:17:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mitchtech.github.io/hugo-mitchtech/vnc-setup-on-raspberry-pi-from-android/</guid>
      <description>This tutorial will demonstrate how to setup and connect to a Raspberry Pi over VNC from Android. This process assumes you have Debian for Raspberry Pi installed on an SD card. If not, see RPi Easy SD card setup. It also assumes that you have a display connected to the Raspberry Pi. If you don&amp;rsquo;t have a display available, the steps to configure VNC remotely are outlined in my last tutorial: VNC setup on Raspberry Pi from Ubuntu</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VNC setup on Raspberry Pi from Ubuntu</title>
      <link>https://mitchtech.github.io/hugo-mitchtech/vnc-setup-on-raspberry-pi-from-ubuntu/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jun 2012 18:02:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mitchtech.github.io/hugo-mitchtech/vnc-setup-on-raspberry-pi-from-ubuntu/</guid>
      <description>This tutorial will demonstrate how to setup and connect to a Raspberry Pi over VNC from Ubuntu. This process is easier if you have a display connected to the Raspberry Pi, but will also show the steps to connect with only Ethernet and power connected. It assumes you have Debian for Raspberry Pi installed on an SD card. If not, see RPi Easy SD card setup
Getting the IP address of the Raspberry Pi The first step is to locate the Raspberry Pi on your network.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>