<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Openni on Mitchtech</title>
    <link>https://mitchtech.github.io/hugo-mitchtech/tags/openni/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Openni on Mitchtech</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Powered by [Hugo](//gohugo.io). Theme by [PPOffice](http://github.com/ppoffice).</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 May 2012 15:58:13 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mitchtech.github.io/hugo-mitchtech/tags/openni/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenCV &#43; Python</title>
      <link>https://mitchtech.github.io/hugo-mitchtech/opencv-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2012 15:58:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mitchtech.github.io/hugo-mitchtech/opencv-python/</guid>
      <description>Here are some of the more interesting OpenCV demos using the Python wrapper. The installation process on Ubuntu is covered in my previous post, OpenCV + Ubuntu. The demo scripts are located in samples/python within the OpenCV release.
The cam shift sample below demonstrates the color/object detection capability of OpenCV. To set the object/color to track, click and drag a box on the video using the mouse. The histogram window will display the target for OpenCV to locate and track within the field of view.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenCV &#43; Ubuntu</title>
      <link>https://mitchtech.github.io/hugo-mitchtech/opencv-ubuntu/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2012 15:52:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mitchtech.github.io/hugo-mitchtech/opencv-ubuntu/</guid>
      <description>Building OpenCV 2.3.1 from source on Ubuntu 12.04 x64. Here is an overview of the compilation of OpenCV with x264 and ffmpeg builtin. If you have completed my Kinect + OpenNI + PrimeSensetutorial, this will also support the OpenNI and PrimeSense drivers with OpenCV. This is largely based on the wonderful OpenCV tutorials from Sebastian Montabone and Osman Eralp. Before you start, make sure to have removed ffmpeg and x264 (if applicable):</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu &#43; Kinect &#43; OpenNI &#43; PrimeSense</title>
      <link>https://mitchtech.github.io/hugo-mitchtech/ubuntu-kinect-openni-primesense/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2012 05:15:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mitchtech.github.io/hugo-mitchtech/ubuntu-kinect-openni-primesense/</guid>
      <description>Getting the OpenNI and PrimeSense drivers working on Ubuntu Here’s an overview of the process to get the OpenNI and PrimeSense drivers working with the Kinect and Ubuntu. Begin by installing some dependencies:
sudo apt-get install git-core cmake freeglut3-dev pkg-config build-essential libxmu-dev libxi-dev libusb-1.0-0-dev doxygen graphviz mono-complete  Make a directory to store the build, then clone the OpenNI source from Github.
mkdir ~/kinect cd ~/kinect git clone https://github.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>